

PYTHON ENGINEER · PHD (COMPUTER SCIENCE

Amsterdam. The Netherlands

publications (Scopus) | ☐ dmitrii-altukhov-258b05233 | ☑ altukhov.dm@gmail.com | ☐ +316 136 36 770

Profile ____

For the past 8 years, I've been occupied in neuroimaging research. My projects involved software development, data engineering, and data science as well as technical writing and presentation. I'm a lifelong learner striving for novelty and passionate about AI, code quality and design.

Skills _____

Python, Numpy, PyTorch, Numba, SQL, Docker, Linux

Experience _____

SBDA Group

Astana, Kazakhstan (remote)

Data scientist, contract Sep. 2023 – Oct. 2023

• Developed and implemented a tool for optimizing manufacturing schedule in **Python**

Artificial Intelligence Research Institute (AIRI)

Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH FELLOW Feb. 2022 – Apr. 2023

- Built deep learning model for decoding speech from MEG data in PyTorch, meg_speech_decoding on github
- Developed real-time pipeline for EEG timeseries analysis using Python

Higher School of Economics, Centre for Cognition and Decision Making

Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH FELLOW, PYTHON SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2021

- Led 4-people group developing software for real-time ML and 3D visualization of brain activity from EEG using Python + Numba JIT
- Created a pipeline for MEG data preprocessing, see metacognition, MRI_metacognition on github

University of Montreal, CERNEC lab., and Moscow MEG Center

Montreal, Canada, Moscow, Russia

VISITING RESEARCHER, TEMPORARY POSITION

Feb 2015 - Dec 2018

- · Built a classifier for ASD patients vs. Controls with 75% accuracy using classical ML and information geometry in Python
- Co-developed an open-source Python package for heavy neuroimaging data processing, Neuropycon
- Published four papers in collaboration with the University of Montreal

Scientific Research Institute of System Analysis

Moscow, Russia Jun. 2011 – Jan. 2015

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, PROMOTED TO JUNIOR RESEARCH FELLOW

• Tested software for simulations of flow in jet engines; implemented a droplet evaporation model in C++

Education ____

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Moscow, Russia

HIGHER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS, FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jan. 2016 - Nov. 2021

- Thesis: "Optimal methods for functional connectivity estimation in magnetoencephalography."; GPA: 4.0
- Published a paper in a leading neuroscientific journal (see Ossadtchi et al. [2018]) by proposing an algorithm for brain signals analysis.

Specialist degree in Mechanics (Masters equivalent)

Moscow, Russia

LOMONOSOV MOSCOW STATE UNIVERSITY, DEPARTMENT OF MECHANICS AND MATHEMATICS

Sep. 2008 - Jun. 2013

Thesis: "Enhancement and validation of LOGOS software for simulations of the reactive fluid flows."

Honors & Awards ____

• Selected for 2-year HSE Academic Scholarship for a high-impact publication

Moscow, Russia

2019

St. Petersburg, Russia

* Selected 1-st out of 5 teams *IEEE Brain Data Bank Challenge* for building a BCI drinking game

etersburg, Russia 2017